Antoine Soetewey

antoinesoetewey.com

Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical procedures applied to cancer patients. In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching assistant for several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level and I provide trainings and workshops in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service. In my spare time, I write about statistics and code in R via my blog statsandr.com.

Education

| Education |
|---|
| PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium - Thesis: Life and health actuarial pricing: a biostatistics approach (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit) - All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research |
| MSc in econometrics & operations research – Maastricht University, Netherlands - Thesis: <i>Combining professional and survey forecasts for macroeconomic data</i> (supervisor: Prof. Nalan Basturk) |
| MSc in economics – KULeuven, Belgium - Thesis: Negativity bias and framing effect in charity donations: a field experiment (supervisor: Prof. Jo Swinnen) |
| Faculty exchange – University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA |
| BSc in economics & management sciences – UCLouvain, Belgium |
| Teaching and consulting experience |
| Teaching assistant in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium |
| - See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching |
| |
| |

2018 – Present Private tutor in statistics and consultant in data science – Self-employed

- Private tutor for students and academics. See more information at easystat.be
- Data science consultant for professionals and companies. See more information at datanalyze.be

Industry experience

2016 – 2017 Data scientist – Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization
- 2015 European public affairs intern BNP Paribas, Belgium
- 2015 **Audit intern** Deloitte, Luxembourg

Leadership experience

2017 – Present International tennis chair umpire – International Tennis Federation

- Work regularly as a chair or line umpire on major tennis events across the world

2016 – Present Committee member – Association Francophone de Tennis, Belgium

Technical skills & languages

Software

- R (RStudio, R Markdown, Shiny), GitHub/GitLab, LATEX
- See all projects at antoinesoetewey.com/software

Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (intermediate)